# RAPHAEL NEUMANN

raphael@rneumann.me | +55 61 98283-3094 https://www.linkedin.com/in/raphael-neumann Brasília DF

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Industrious DevOps Engineer offering 10 years background setting up CI and CD pipelines and scripting deployment activities with solid background in software engineering. Well-rounded and conscientious professional committed to proactively managing change and quickly deploying critical applications building successful tools to reduce error occurrences and conducting root cause analysis. Expertise in configuration management and Agile, Scrum and Waterfall methodologies. Familiar with Typescript and Python.

### **SKILLS**

- Kubernetes
- Incident Management
- Cloud Computing Expertise
- Scripting Languages
- Infrastructure Automation
- Google Cloud Platform (GCP)

- Monitoring and Logging
- Microservices Architecture
- Containerization Technologies
- Configuration Management
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)

#### **WORK HISTORY**

**Senior DevOps Engineer** | 2K UK (Mindera) - United Kingdon (Remote)

- Developed custom scripts using Python or Bash languages to 10/2023 Current automate repetitive tasks or integrate disparate systems effectively streamlining workflows across departments.
- Streamlined infrastructure management through automation using industry-leading tools such as Ansible, Kubernetes, and Terraform.
- Manage dedicated Kubernetes cluster provisioned on AWS Cloud.
- Created team strategy for SDLC automation, configuration management and release management.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to drive continuous improvement in the software delivery process.
- Maintained metrics visibility using Datadog and Prometheus/Grafana to create useful dashboards and monitors.

Senior DevOps Engineer | Fanduel/FoxBet (Mindera) - New York, United States

- Worked with internal teams to migrate applications to

  Kubernetes, redesigning pipelines to reduce time to deployment (TTD) significantly from several weeks to a few days.
- Implemented Dynamic Environments to enable software development teams to deploy and test their code without worrying about the environment's concurrency.

- Infrastructure Terraform code refactoring, which combines the creation of private Terraform modules and the import of all existing infrastructure into the Terraform manifest, archiving 100% of the infrastructure as code (IaC) adoption.
- Implemented ArgoCD as the primary GitOps tool used to manage the Continuous Delivery (CD) process.
- Monitoring of all applications and infrastructure with DataDog.
- Participate in on-call rotation to support the application during incidents.

## **Lead DevOps Engineer** | Sharecare - Full Remote

02/2021 - 08/2022

- Implement Kubernetes to support new microservices applications on GCP
- Restructuring AWS infrastructure to new multi-account architecture and implementing Kubernetes to replace swarm
- Work closely with the developer team to architecting best practices and solves microservice architecture
- All infrastructure has built Code using tools such as Kustomize and ArgoCD.

# Senior DevOps Engineer | Tata Consultancy Services - TCS - Full Remote

• Maintaining a Datalake tools and pipeline using Kubenetes, 03/2020 - 03/2021Terraform, Google Bigguery and Elastic Search at main technologies.

# Lead of Infrastructure | Xerpa - São Paulo, SP

03/2019 - 03/2020

- Implementing and managing of Kubernetes cluster
- Administration of AWS critical and productive infrastructure
- Provision and management of infrastructure using Terraform and Ansible
- Architecture and implementation of CI/CD pipelines.

# Services Consultant | CA Technologies - São Paulo, SP

09/2018 - 03/2019

- Implementing CA Products on customer's site
- JAVA EE application, Elastic Search cluster and Kafka Cluster implementation, maintenance and monitoring.

## DevOps Engineer | B2br - Brasília, DF

02/2016 - 08/2018

- Create pipelines for automatic deploy and integration
- Linux system administration whit Puppet
- Maintenance of Java and PHP Applications
- Scripting in Shell, Python and Ruby

#### **EDUCATION**

Faculdade Atual - Brasilia, DF **Bachelor's in system information** 

01/2015

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Puppet Certified Professional, 2017, PCP205-0073
- Zend Certified PHP Engineer, ZEND027075

### **LANGUAGES**

Portuguese - Native

English - Advance